Guide to the Lennig Sweet Papers
Yale University Divinity School Library
Lennig Sweet Papers
1915-1974
RG 150
Yale University Divinity School Library
0.5
(1 box)
Letters, reports, and printed material document the work of the Peking (Beijing) YMCA, which was sponsored by Princeton-in-Peking. Lennig Sweet served the YMCA in Beijing, China between 1916 and 1934. He later worked for United China Relief from 1942 to 1947 and as YMCA Secretary for Overseas Staff and YMCA Secretary in Seoul, Korea.
Sweet, Lennig, 1893-1973
Conditions Governing Access
Open to qualified researchers.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Gift of the Sweet family.
Biographical / Historical
1893 Sep 24 Born in Denver, Colorado, son of Joyeuse Fullerton and William Ellery Sweet. WES was Governor of Colorado, 1922-1924.
1916 B.A., Princeton
1916Sep-1917 Aug Princeton University Center in China YMCA, Peking, teacher of recreation and English.
1918 Apr-1919Jan U.S. Army Signal Corps
1918 Oct Married Helen Firman of Oak Park, IL, a graduate of Mt. Holyoke who later received Master's degree from Columbia and taught home economics at Yenching University. Children: Joyeuse (b.1922), Helen (b.1929), Elizabeth (b.1932)
1919 Jan-1920 Sep YMCA Secretary-in-training, Cleveland
1920 Sep-1936 Employee of International Committee of YMCAs of U.S. and Canada
1920-1926; 1930-1934 YMCA, Peking. Boys work Secretary; Director, Training Center; General Secretary; Yenching University, Peking Lecturer, Group Work and Social Work Administration.
1926-1929 Graduate study: Columbia (M.A. 1928, Ph.D. 1930); Union Theological Seminary (Ph.D. 1929)
1935 National Committee, YMCAs of China, Personnel Secretary and Director of Training.
1935-1936 National Board, YMCAs of U.S.,. Public speaking and fund raising.
1936 Jul-1942Mar Social Security Administration, Washington, D.C.
1942 May-1947 Sep United China Relief, N.Y. and Chungking
1945 Jan-Aug UNRRA, China
1948-1956 YMCA Secretary for Overseas Staff
1956-1958 YMCA Secretary, Seoul, Korea
1973 Nov Died
Scope and Contents
This small but substantive collection of letters, reports and printed material is particularly useful for its documentation of the work of the Peking YMCA, which was sponsored by Princeton-in-Peking. The papers complement other holdings at YDSL, including the papers of Sweet's colleagues Dwight Edwards (RG 12) and Lyman Hoover (RG 9) and extensive documentation of the Princeton work in China available in the Archives of the United Board for Christian Higher Education in Asia (RG 11 and RG 11A).
The Correspondence of Series I includes twenty-seven letters, primarily from Sweet to his parents and grandparents, which provide insightful description and comment of political conditions, famine relief projects and subjects like industry in Peking. The reports of Series II are substantive documents, primarily written to provide information to supporters in the U.S.
Arrangement
I. Correspondence, 1916-1932, n.d.
II. Writings/ Reports, 1916-1946, n.d.
III. Printed Material, 1916-1935, n.d.
IV. Biographical Documentation, 1917-1974
V. Photographs, 1915-1956,n.d.
Young Men's Christian Associations -- China; Sweet, Lennig, 1893-1973; Princeton University Center in China; United China Relief (U.S.)
- Correspondence, 1916-1932, n.d.; Series I
  - Family correspondence, 1916-1918 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Family correspondence, 1921-1925 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Family correspondence, 1930-1932, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Writings/ Reports, 1916-1946, n.d; Series II
  - Reports
    - Report letters / drafts, 1916-1917 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Report letters / drafts, 1920-1921 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Report letters / drafts, 1932, 1933, 1946, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Annual administration reports, Peking YMCA, 1917, 1921 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Annual administration reports, Peking YMCA, 1922-1927 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Annual administration reports, Peking YMCA, 1933-1934 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Other writings by LS
    - Typescript report re. Peking YMCA, 1935 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - The Measurement of Personal Attitudes in Younger Boys (Association Press), 1929 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Writings by others
    - Report of conference of foreign secretaries and their wives re. residences in China (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Account of journey into Kansu and Tibet by Dean of Canterbury (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Printed Material, 1916-1935, n.d.; Series III
  - Regarding Peking YMCA, 1925-1935 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Regarding Princeton-in-Peking, 1916-1925 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Regarding Rotary Club of Peking, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 16)
- Biographical Documentation, 1917-1974; Series IV
  - Incl. employment history, 1917-1958 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Incl. audiotape of interview for article in the Denver Post, 1970-1974 (Box 1, Folder 18)
- Photographs, 1915-1956,n.d.; Series V
  - Portrait of LS, 1956 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Princeton-in-Peking representatives, 1934 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Sherwood Eddy visit to Peking, 1932 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Additional photos related to YMCA and famine relief, 1915, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 19)